If you have any kind of
bike and
want to get it insured, then in today's video I'm going to
tell you how you
can do it from your mobile sitting at home.
Let's start the video without any delay.
So first of all, let me tell you
where you have to get the insurance done because many
people after watching my video face
issues on Google 2 because
after the payment, the KYC process stops
and due to which your money gets stuck.
So if you
check the link given in my video, you wo
n't face any such problem.
Also, if you have any issue, you can call me and
I will help you. So
let me tell you how to do it. What
you have to do for that, if you
look below in this video of mine, there is a link given in the comments.
So suppose you are
watching this video of ours, just below this video
you will see there is a comment section. If you
click on it, you will
see a link. You can see that this
is the link. You have to open it in this way,
so I have given this direct link.  So that
after coming you have to give your bike number, that is,
you have to give the vehicle number here,
so I have given my vehicle number
and after that
you have to click on view price, if
you want to know how much will the
insurance cost, so many people now
ask me
how will I do it for the new vehicle I am buying, so if you are buying a new vehicle then
you can do it from here also,
what you have to do if you see below,
this option of new bike is written,
click here, you have to do it
by clicking on it, ok and if your vehicle
number has come then you have to give this number
here, give both the options here, you
can process both from here, so let's go, I have
put the vehicle number,
after that I will click on view price, when I
click, all the information of the bike will be taken
automatically, so you will
not need to give it here, you just have to
tell which type of policy you want,
see here one is written
comprehensive, the second is written third
party, what is the difference between these two, I will
explain to you  Let me give you this, suppose your
car met with an accident and
you want to claim for it, then you have to choose comprehensive here
and if you do
not want to claim for your car and are doing it just to
escape from the police, then
you can do third party, I will explain the rest of the details to
you later on, wherever required,
so right now suppose you want to do
first party, then you have to
choose comprehensive here, you can see, there is this
option of comprehensive here, if
I choose it, then our
car will also be covered in it and third party
means this is also included in it, so if
you choose this, then it is an all in one
thing, okay, after that, coming down, you will
see the option of pay view course here,
you have to click on it, after which
you can see here that it will
open automatically in this way and
you will get the list of all the companies, you can see, the
list of all of them is given that for which company
how much will it cost, Digit will do
951, United will do 06, all these things are
given here which
This ID is also given in the middle, it means
that the price of your vehicle is
set by the insurance company, which is the
minimum price. If you find it less,
you can increase it. But
before that, what is this ID? If you don't
know, then I will explain. It means
that the value of your vehicle, if your
vehicle gets damaged or for some reason the bus gets
destroyed and you don't have the vehicle, then the
insurance company will give you this amount, that is, if it is
20,000, then it will give you only 20,000. You have to
understand that if the ID of your vehicle
is less here and you will get more,
this does not happen, so if you find it less, then
you can increase it. I will tell you how to increase it.
You will see this at the top, this
ID is also written in the middle. If you
click on it from here,
it will open. You have to simply
select the maximum which is in the middle and
click on update. Then you will
see that the rates of all have
increased. You can see this.  Its has become 0000,
its is only 19000, its has also become 0000, in
this way you will see the rates of different companies,
so in this way you can increase the ID also, so right
now the rate it is showing is for
only 1 year, if
you want to do it for more than 1 year then from here
you can change it in plan type,
2 years, 3 years, in this way you
get the option, you can choose the number of years you want, let's keep it for
one year only,
I am crossing it,
ok, after that comes NCB, it is called no claim bonus, its
meaning is that if you do
not take any claim from the previous insurance company, then this
year you get the benefit, in case of bike it is very
negligible, so there will be no difference,
but in case of card there is a lot of
difference, ok, so let's do this
NCB here, now here
two options of comprehensive and zero depreciation are given,
you should understand its meaning also because
in the beginning I told about host time  If
you take the comprehensive one, you will get everything. Now, if you only take the comprehensive one, in this you will get
only 50 to 60 rupees, but
you will not get any claim more than that.
Suppose there is an accident and
something in your car gets damaged,
suppose the headlight is broken or something else gets
damaged, then you get only about 50 rupees for that.
If you want more, okay, that
means you want that I will
not pay even Rs. If I am taking insurance, then
normally people think that if
I take insurance then why would I
pay otherwise, if you want your 100% claim, then
for such a case you have to go towards zero,
okay, so the same
option is given here, you can see
comprehensive and thirdly, give zero here, then
choose this one, so you can see here that
normally since the car is more than 5 years
old, then not all the companies are giving it, it
is available only from one company which
gives this much amount of Rs. 1331 on IDB.  If I
press zero of this company, then in case of any
accident, the
insurance company will pay all the money, I just have to pay the filing
charges, okay, and if you
take comprehensive, then you will get it for around 50, for
50 you will have to pay from your pocket,
so these were all the things that are added,
if you do an insurance then you need to
know before that, let me come back to
comprehensive and
choose any company, suppose
I want to do United, then I will
choose this one, now if you see here,
all the details of the vehicle owner are being
asked here, so here the name is being asked,
now of course my name is already there, then there is
no need to give it, if it is not there then
you can give it, you can give any mobile number here,
you can give the owner's mobile number
also, you can give yours or anyone's, there is
no problem, you
can give anyone's email ID also, but
you will have to give the name only of the owner, you can give the address, the
address is normally written on the RC,
check from there  You
can give it, okay, you will have to give the rest of the city, UT, everything,
let me come down,
after coming down you will see that the
pin code is not given here, see the
city is given but the pin code is not given,
so I will give the pin code here,
but if it is in your case then you will
not need to give this also, if not then
you may have to give everything,
after doing this it is asking here whether there is a
loan on the vehicle, if there is a loan then say yes and if you say yes then you will have to
tell from which company
you have taken the loan, in which city you have to
tell both the things, of course my
vehicle does not have any loan, so I am selecting no
and after that I am
seeing next here, I am clicking on it,
after which KYC
comes here, here you should have your
PAN card in the KYC document, only then
you can do KYC,
otherwise you cannot do it, the
rule being said here is that KYC will be in the
name of the owner of the vehicle,
suppose the vehicle is in my name, then you can put your
PAN card  You cannot do it under any circumstances,
many people do it, they do it, it is
a different thing but the rule says
that you should give the PAN card of the owner of the vehicle
and you can do the KYC with that PAN card only,
so let me give my PAN card here
because the vehicle is in my name,
let me give my PAN card number and
here I will give the date of birth, for that if you
click on it then the calendar will open, you will select the
year, month and
date, all three things have to be selected from here,
so I have selected both the things,
after that I will click on verify, when
I click on verify then it will
automatically start getting verified and after
verification it will come in this way that
see both have come green,
it means that your KYC is complete,
now you do not have to do anything, you simply have to
click on submit, after which it will
ask for the engine number in the additional details, it will be automatically with you,
so you do not need to give it, you
simply have to click on the submit button,
now you have to click on this here  It comes in this way,
so what you have to do is
click on the Pay Secure Li button to make the payment
so that you get the policy copy. As soon as you
click on the payment button, it will
take you to the payment page of the Pay Bazaar. Now
what you have to do is, here you get the
option of debit card i.e. ATM card, credit card option,
net banking option, UPI
wallet option, so
you can make the payment through whichever one you want to make the payment. Nowadays, most of the
people have PhonePe, I will give you PhonePe
and here I will have to give you the UPI
ID, so whatever your UPI
ID is, you have to give it here and
after that, what is there, you select the handle, what will happen,
you will
see in your UPI ID, you will find it, I have
selected it and after that, you are looking at Pay, you will
click on it, so if you see it at the top, then the
message will keep coming in this way and when you
open PhonePe, you can see that a
payment request has come in this way.
What you have to do is click on it,
like you will click on Pay,
as soon as you click on Pay,  This is
how you do UPI to someone on your phone,
you have to make this payment in the same way as you do it normally, just like you
make a payment, you do not have to press the back button,
you have to come back to this page, to the
PSI Bazaar page and after coming here
you have to wait, you will see that
normally in three to four seconds it will automatically
refresh and will
give you the option to download the POLOS copy, from there you
can download it in PDF form and
when you download it, that POLOS
copy will be yours, what you have to do is get it
printed from any cyber cap near you
and that will serve as the original, in
this way you
can easily insure your bike from your mobile, I hope you have
understood everything, if you have any
confusion, if you want to know something then ask by commenting below,
I will definitely tell you,
that's all for now in this video, thank you very much.